Guide to the Norman Macleod Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1911-1985; Series I; 17.51; (42 boxes)
  - Weise, Fr. Thomas D., 1977-1980 (Box 41, Folder 401)
  - West, John Foster, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 402)
  - Whisnant, Charleen, 1971-1973 (Box 41, Folder 403)
  - White, Jim, 1974-1981 (Box 41, Folder 404)
  - Wiggins, Forrest Oran, 1966-1967 (Box 41, Folder 405)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1969 (Box 41, Folder 406)
  - Williams, William Carlos, 1935-1954 (Box 41, Folder 407)
  - Witemeyer, Hugh, incoming and outgoing, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 408)
  - Wixson, Douglas
    - Incoming, 1981-1984 (Box 42, Folder 409)
    - Outgoing, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 410)
  - Wolber, Daniel, incoming and outgoing, 1977-1978 (Box 42, Folder 411)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1935-1939 (Box 42, Folder 412)
  - "Y" General, 1973, undated (Box 42, Folder 413)
  - Yale University Library, 1968-1983 (Box 42, Folder 414)
  - Young Bear, Ray, outgoing, 1970-1971 (Box 42, Folder 415)
  - "Z" General, 1969-1974 (Box 42, Folder 416)
  - Unidentified, incoming and outgoing, 1934-1977; 2 (Box 42, Folder 417-418)
- Writings, 1923-1984; Series II; 2.92; (7 boxes)
  Writings consist of drafts (autograph manuscript and typescript, some corrected) of MacLeod's poetry, novels, and autobiography, as well as notes and other related material. Unless otherwise noted, titles refer to poems or compilations of poems. A few files contain proofs or associated material, as indicated in folder descriptions.
  Organized into two subseries: Writings of Norman Macleod, and Writings of Others.
  - Writings of Norman Macleod
    Arranged alphabetically by title. Untitled works are filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "About Skye and Bali Hai, a fellow traveler, (for a time) and a special island", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 419)
    - "About traveling about and up", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 420)
    - Adam's off ox, circa 1950; 3 (Box 43, Folder 421-423)
    - "An aerogramme to Liam Hunt in Somerset", 1984 (Box 43, Folder 424)
    - "After the real jazz went to Chinatown", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 425)
    - "An apology to Wallace Stevens", 1984 (Box 43, Folder 426)
    - "Austrian archdukes ought to go home where they came from", 1984 (Box 43, Folder 427)
    - "Before the smog buried Missoula", 1984 (Box 43, Folder 428)
    - The Bitter Roots (novel), proofs, 1941 (Box 43, Folder 429)
    - "Blue disaster," typescript, undated (Box 43, Folder 430)
    - "A Cezanne of Shane the gunslinger riding toward Sainte-Victoire", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 431)
    - "Communication for CS", undated (Box 43, Folder 432)
    - "Cowled with darkness", undated (Box 43, Folder 433)
    - "The deep of night below Trachas Mountain", undated (Box 43, Folder 434)
    - "The descent", 1984; 3 (Box 43, Folder 435-437)
    - The Distance: new and selected poems (1928-1977)
      - Typescript, 1977; 4 (Box 44, Folder 438-441)
      - Printed version, 1977 (Box 44, Folder 442)
    - "Don't leave your wife at the first invitation", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 443)
    - "The end of the trail, or the trail's end, or, The end and the beginning", 1923 (Box 44, Folder 444)
    - "The evening will come", undated (Box 44, Folder 445)
    - "Everyone knows Wallace Stevens was a communist", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 446)
    - Family of flying apart, undated (Box 44, Folder 447)
    - "A flower in spring in southern Utah", 1976 (Box 44, Folder 448)
    - "For Catherine", 1981 (Box 44, Folder 449)
    - "From San Juan Capistrano to Hungry Horse, Montana", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 450)
    - "From shelled out Frankfurt to posterity", 1985 (Box 44, Folder 451)
    - Generation of Anger: A Writer in the Twentieth Century (autobiography)
      - Index, Part 1, undated; 3 (Box 44, Folder 452-454)
      - Parts 1-4, undated; 5 (Box 45, Folder 455-459)
      - Part 5, undated (Box 46, Folder 460)
      - Quotes, 1956 (Box 46, Folder 461)
    - Get on a Horse and Ride (autobiographical novel), 1932-1941; 2 (Box 46, Folder 462-463)
    - "The girl from Saks Fifth Avenue", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 464)
    - "A girl on the green", undated (Box 46, Folder 465)
    - "A great jazz band died with World War II", 1985 (Box 46, Folder 466)
    - "Harry forgot to tell us", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 467)
    - "Hobbs" (travel article), 1930 (Box 46, Folder 468)
    - "Hopscotching before second childhood", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 469)
    - "How the tall corn grows out of a Des Moines sportscaster", 1985 (Box 46, Folder 470)
    - "I never lost anything in Istanbul", undated (Box 46, Folder 471)
    - "It should never be so hot", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 472)
    - "I've been thinking about you, Lady Cameron", 1984, undated (Box 46, Folder 473)
    - "Kris stands there with arms akimbo", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 474)
    - "The leopard frozen on top of Kilimanjaro", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 475)
    - "Lions strike what they're looking at", 1985 (Box 46, Folder 476)
    - "A lobster dinner with Augie", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 477)
    - "The Lord gets around a lot", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 478)
    - "A mad Miturator way of looking at things", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 479)
    - A Man in Midpassage, accompanying artwork by Ralston Crawford, circa 1952 (Box 46, Folder 480)
    - "Motion of Years", undated (Box 46, Folder 481)
    - "My Father was never a faithful Hussar", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 482)
    - "My Mother is feeling, then", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 483)
    - "My travel agent, St. Christopher Black", 1985 (Box 46, Folder 484)
    - "The neckbone is connected to the headbone", 1984 (Box 46, Folder 485)
    - "NHP", 1973 (Box 46, Folder 486)
    - "The New Los Angeles is being erected in honor of Yevgeny Yevtushenko and his Bratsk station", 1972 (Box 46, Folder 487)
    - New Mexico Department of Public Welfare. Reports, 1952-953; 2 (Box 46, Folder 488-489)
    - "No, we have some bananas at Newport, Yes!", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 490)
    - "Not even the J. P. always wins", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 491)
    - "Nothing is real anyway", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 492)
    - "People with the most money can screw things up better", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 493)
    - "A poem for Fran", undated (Box 47, Folder 494)
    - "Political Formation: Lessons for the 'Arrows'", undated (Box 47, Folder 495)
    - "Prairie steel", undated (Box 47, Folder 496)
    - Pure as nowhere (microfilm), 1975
    - "A quandry I am in", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 497)
    - "A question for Military Santeros making a holy image", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 498)
    - "Rhubarb I always left on the ground", 1984-1985 (Box 47, Folder 499)
    - "Robert Frost said 'Ice would be nice,' but fire would suffice for both of us", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 500)
    - "A Scotch thistle for W. S. Graham", 1974 (Box 47, Folder 501)
    - "The seagulls are crying for you, Jock", 1975 (Box 47, Folder 502)
    - "Sing, you sinners!", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 503)
    - "Something of blind benefit", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 504)
    - "Sweet Potato Pie Jones", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 505)
    - "To all Scottish Gaelic speaking seagulls"
      See: "Wireless: to all Gaelic gulls"
    - "T.V. antennae are the church spires of our culture", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 506)
    - "T.V.'s latest massacre of the past", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 507)
    - "Two girls in Santa Fe", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 508)
    - "Way back in Neanderthal days", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 509)
    - "We need more ice for the party", 1985 (Box 47, Folder 510)
    - "What the big boss is about", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 511)
    - "Why don't you go ahead and die where you're at, Jack?"
      See: "About Skye and Bali Hai, a fellow traveler, (for a time) and a special island"
    - "Who could ever regret having seen Rita Hayworth?", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 512)
    - "Wireless: to all Gaelic gulls", 1984 (Box 47, Folder 513)
    - Unsorted poems (various titles), circa 1930, undated; 5 (Box 47, Folder 514-518)
    - Material for memoir
      - Notes, 1970-1972; 2 (Box 47, Folder 519-520)
      - Notes (Continued), 1973-1984; 10 (Box 48, Folder 521-530)
      - "Memoir file", 1969-1985 (Box 48, Folder 531)
      - "Memoir file" (Continued), 1969-1985 (Box 49, Folder 532)
    - Writings by Norman Macleod that appeared in The New Masses (microfilm), 1980
  - Writings of Others
    Organized under two headings: About Norman Macleod, and Other Writings.
    - About Norman Macleod
      Arranged alphabetically by author. Unidentified writings are filed at the end.
      Material filed under this heading consists of typescript drafts unless otherwise indicated.
      - Blackmur, R. P. Review of Horizons of Death, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 533)
      - Dalmas, Victor
        - "Norman Macleod: modern American surrealist", 1973 (Box 49, Folder 534)
        - "The poetry of Norman Macleod", 1972-1973; 2 (Box 49, Folder 535-536)
        - Review of Selected Poems, printed version, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 537)
      - G_____, A. O. Cincinatti Inquirer, review of You Get What You Ask For, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 538)
      - Grimes, James, "Norman Macleod and Pembroke Magazine", 1977 (Box 49, Folder 539)
      - Hotvedt, Kris, "A recollection of Norman Macleod", 1972 (Box 49, Folder 540)
      - MacLeish, Archibald "Outline for rewriting and reorganizing of the two novels in mss, Get what you ask for and Escape from chaos, to constitute one novel", 1939 (Box 49, Folder 541)
      - Marsh, Fred T., review of The Bitter Roots, printed version, 1941 (Box 49, Folder 542)
      - Meurant, Rene, review of Horizons of Death, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 543)
      - Nelson, Helen, review of The Bitter Roots, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 544)
      - Pearce, T. M., "Norman Macleod as I remember him", 1973 (Box 49, Folder 545)
      - Putnam, Samuel, "Norman Macleod, or nerves and the revolution", 1935 (Box 49, Folder 546)
      - Wald, Alan. Review of The Distance, printed version, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 547)
      - Williams, William Carlos
        - "A poem for Norman Macleod", undated (Box 49, Folder 548)
        - Reviews, 1968, undated (Box 49, Folder 549)
      - Various authors. Reviews., 1934, 1937; 2 (Box 49, Folder 550-551)
      - Unidentified. "Poets and prose writers of America," La Mañana, Montevideo, Uraguay, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 552)
    - Other Writings
      - Macleod, Ann Clark, "Description of a meeting with Ezra Pound," typescript, 1968 (Box 49, Folder 553)
      - The Perfect Advocate: A Brief life of the Late Hugh B. Cox, draft, typescript, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 554)
- Pembroke Magazine Records, 1968-1981; Series III; 5.84; (14 boxes)
  This series consists of the records of Pembroke Magazine during the tenure of Norman Macleod as founding editor (1969-1978). Material includes correspondence, submissions, production files, and financial records.
  Organized into four subseries: Correspondence, Contributor Files, Production Files, and Administrative Records.
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted Correspondence, 1971-1977; 7 (Box 50, Folder 555-561)
    - Unsorted Correspondence, 1973-1977; 5 (Box 51, Folder 562-566)
  - Contributor Files
    Include authors' submissions, and associated correspondence.
    - Abril, Xavier, 1968 (Box 51, Folder 567)
    - Ackley, Brenda, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 568)
    - Ackley, Randall, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 569)
    - Adair, V.H., undated (Box 51, Folder 570)
    - Aldrich, Myrl, undated (Box 51, Folder 571)
    - Allen, Paula, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 572)
    - Als, Michael, undated (Box 51, Folder 573)
    - Arnold, Randy, undated (Box 51, Folder 574)
    - Atkinson, Brooks, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 575)
    - Ault, J. Burchenal, undated (Box 51, Folder 576)
    - Avery, Judy, undated (Box 51, Folder 577)
    - Baggett, Jack M., undated (Box 51, Folder 578)
    - Barnes, Dick, undated (Box 51, Folder 579)
    - Barrington, Jay, undated (Box 51, Folder 580)
    - Bate, W.J., 1975 (Box 51, Folder 581)
    - Bayes, Ronald H., 1972 (Box 51, Folder 582)
    - Bendell, Donald R., undated (Box 51, Folder 583)
    - Bennett, John Z., undated (Box 51, Folder 584)
    - Berge, Carol, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 585)
    - Boutelle, Ann, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 586)
    - Boyd, Su Abbott, undated (Box 51, Folder 587)
    - Brown, Bryan, undated (Box 51, Folder 588)
    - Brown, Michael, undated (Box 51, Folder 589)
    - Brown, Sterling A., 1970 (Box 51, Folder 590)
    - Bruchac, Joseph, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 591)
    - Butterick, George, undated (Box 52, Folder 592)
    - Caldwell, Erskin, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 593)
    - Carlile, Robert, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 594)
    - Chang, Diana, undated (Box 52, Folder 595)
    - Cho, Sungyo, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 596)
    - Clark, Steve, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 597)
    - Conley, Robert J., 1971 (Box 52, Folder 598)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, undated (Box 52, Folder 599)
    - Crews, Judson, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 600)
    - Dalmas, Victor P., undated (Box 52, Folder 601)
    - Dawson, Juanita, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 602)
    - Degasperi, Mark, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 603)
    - Delgado, Abelerado, undated (Box 52, Folder 604)
    - Dockery, Carl, undated (Box 52, Folder 605)
    - Duner, Michael, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 606)
    - Eckman, Frederick, undated (Box 52, Folder 607)
    - Epolito, Joseph, undated (Box 52, Folder 608)
    - Faustin, Charles, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 609)
    - Fitts, Dudley, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 610)
    - Flynt, Tom, undated (Box 52, Folder 611)
    - Forrester, Susan, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 612)
    - Gardner, Geoffrey, undated (Box 52, Folder 613)
    - Godbey, Geoffrey, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 614)
    - Goedicke, Patricia, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 615)
    - Gonzales, Rafel Jesus, undated (Box 52, Folder 616)
    - Graham, W. S., 1972-1974 (Box 52, Folder 617)
    - Green, Paul, 1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 618)
    - Green, Vickie D., undated (Box 52, Folder 619)
    - Gregor, Arthur, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 620)
    - Griffin, Betty, undated (Box 52, Folder 621)
    - Griffin, John, undated (Box 52, Folder 622)
    - Griffin, Walter, 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 623)
    - Grimes, Laura, undated (Box 52, Folder 624)
    - Gustafson, Robert K., 1973 (Box 52, Folder 625)
    - "H" General, 1971-1977 (Box 52, Folder 626)
    - Hall, Donald, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 627)
    - Hall, Vince Norman, undated (Box 52, Folder 628)
    - Hamilton, Fritz, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 629)
    - Hatchell, Mary F., 1971 (Box 52, Folder 630)
    - Hedley, Leslie, undated (Box 52, Folder 631)
    - Herman, Grace, undated (Box 52, Folder 632)
    - Hingle, Pat, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 633)
    - Hogan, Michael, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 634)
    - Hoggard, James, undated (Box 52, Folder 635)
    - Hotvedt, Kris, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 636)
    - Hruska-Cortez, Elias, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 637)
    - Huberman, Elizabeth, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 638)
    - Hudson, William, undated (Box 52, Folder 639)
    - Hulick, Diana, undated (Box 52, Folder 640)
    - Hunt, William, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 641)
    - Jackson, Beth, undated (Box 52, Folder 642)
    - Jackson, Jenny, undated (Box 52, Folder 643)
    - Jacobs, Lucky, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 644)
    - Jean-Baptiste, E. L., 1971 (Box 52, Folder 645)
    - Jenkins, Marshall, undated (Box 52, Folder 646)
    - Johnson, Kurt, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 647)
    - Johnson, Willard, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 648)
    - Kaebitzsch, Reinhold J., 1971 (Box 53, Folder 649)
    - Kalar, Joseph, undated (Box 53, Folder 650)
    - Kazan, Elia, 1975 February 5 (Box 53, Folder 651)
    - Kennedy, Robert C., 1974, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 652)
    - Kim, Chong-un, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 653)
    - Koch, David, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 654)
    - Koch, Vivienne, 1968 December 30 (Box 53, Folder 655)
    - La Fleur, Samuel, undated (Box 53, Folder 656)
    - La Fortune, Knolly S., undated (Box 53, Folder 657)
    - Lau, Alan Chong, 1976, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 658)
    - Lindsay, Maurice, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 659)
    - Lloyd, Linda, undated (Box 53, Folder 660)
    - MacCormack, Harry, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 661)
    - MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 662)
    - Mahapatra, Jayanta, undated (Box 53, Folder 663)
    - Maldonado Little One, Bob, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 664)
    - Martin, Soni, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 665)
    - Maynor, Robert David, 1971-1972 (Box 53, Folder 666)
    - McCord, Howard, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 667)
    - McDonald, Ian, 1972, undated (Box 53, Folder 668)
    - McDonell, Diana G., undated (Box 53, Folder 669)
    - McFarland, Ron, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 670)
    - McKenzie, Donal, undated (Box 53, Folder 671)
    - Menger, Paula, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 672)
    - Miller, Diane, undated (Box 53, Folder 673)
    - Minor, James, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 674)
    - Momaday, N. Scott, undated (Box 53, Folder 675)
    - Morton, Bruce, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 676)
    - Morton, Murray K., undated (Box 53, Folder 677)
    - Moser, Norman, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 678)
    - Murphy, Emily M., undated (Box 53, Folder 679)
    - Nations, Opal, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 680)
    - Ortiz, Simon, 1969-1974 (Box 53, Folder 681)
    - Owen, Guy, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 682)
    - Oxendine, Lloyd E., undated (Box 53, Folder 683)
    - Page, William, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 684)
    - Palmer, Gus, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 685)
    - Pauker, John, undated (Box 53, Folder 686)
    - Pauli, Kenneth, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 687)
    - Peden, William, undated (Box 53, Folder 688)
    - Price, Alexander, undated (Box 53, Folder 689)
    - Prins, Sonja, undated (Box 53, Folder 690)
    - Rachel, Naomi, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 691)
    - Ragan, Sam, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 692)
    - Raisig, Miles, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 693)
    - Rankin, Paula, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 694)
    - Rosenberg, Roger, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 695)
    - Russell, Norman H., 1970 (Box 53, Folder 696)
    - Ryan, W. E., undated (Box 53, Folder 697)
    - Sanchez, Ricardo, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 698)
    - Sato, Hiroko, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 699)
    - Scheele, Karl, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 700)
    - Schevill, James, undated (Box 54, Folder 701)
    - Schipman, Dan, undated (Box 54, Folder 702)
    - Sears, Donald A., 1972 (Box 54, Folder 703)
    - Shaw, Sharon, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 704)
    - Shepherd, Margaret M., 1971 (Box 54, Folder 705)
    - Sherby, Jack, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 706)
    - Sherman, John, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 707)
    - Singh, Bulbul, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 708)
    - Smith, Ian Crichton, undated (Box 54, Folder 709)
    - Smith, Steven, undated (Box 54, Folder 710)
    - Smith, Sydney Goodsir, undated (Box 54, Folder 711)
    - Spivey, Kregg, 1970-1971 (Box 54, Folder 712)
    - Stafford, William, undated (Box 54, Folder 713)
    - Stem, Thad, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 714)
    - Stephenson, Shelby, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 715)
    - Sterling, Ann, 1969, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 716)
    - Strete, Craig Kee, undated (Box 54, Folder 717)
    - Stull, Steve, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 718)
    - Swann, Brian, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 719)
    - Swanson, Donald R., 1973 (Box 54, Folder 720)
    - Tashiro, Taye, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 721)
    - Tate, Allen, 1974-1975 (Box 54, Folder 722)
    - Tolar, Roscoe S., undated (Box 54, Folder 723)
    - Toran, Eugene C., undated (Box 54, Folder 724)
    - Tracy, Liz, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 725)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1973-1975 (Box 54, Folder 726)
    - Van Zandt, Paul, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 727)
    - Vela, Richard, 1971-1975 (Box 54, Folder 728)
    - Vlahos, George, undated (Box 54, Folder 729)
    - Vodvarka, Nancy, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 730)
    - Wallenstein, Barry, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 731)
    - Walters, Tom, 1975-1976 (Box 54, Folder 732)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 733)
    - Watkins, Vernon, undated (Box 54, Folder 734)
    - Whitcomb, Robert, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 735)
    - Wicks, Art, 1976 (Box 54, Folder 736)
    - Wood, Phyllis, undated (Box 54, Folder 737)
    - Worden, Dee, undated (Box 54, Folder 738)
    - Young, Monica, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 739)
    - Young Bear, Ray, 1970-1977 (Box 54, Folder 740)
    - Zimmerman, Toni, undated (Box 55, Folder 741)
    - Zines, Harriet, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 742)
    - Zivkovic, Peter, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 743)
    - Rejected submissions, 1972-1973 (Box 55, Folder 744)
    - Unsorted contributor files, 1973-1976 (Box 55, Folder 745)
  - Production Files, 1969-1981
    Includes correspondence, graphics, mock-ups, and notes.
    - Cumulative index compiled by Miles Raisig, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 746)
    - Cumulative index (microfilm), 1973
    - Issue 1, 1969; 2 (Box 55, Folder 747-748)
    - Issue 2, 1971; 3 (Box 55, Folder 749-751)
    - Issue 3, 1972; 3 (Box 55, Folder 752-754)
    - Issue 4, 1973; 3 (Box 56, Folder 755-757)
    - Issue 5, 1973-1974; 5 (Box 56, Folder 758-762)
    - Issue 5 (microfilm), 1974
    - Issue 6, 1974-1975; 8 (Box 57, Folder 763-770)
    - Issue 6 (continued), 1974-1975; 4 (Box 58, Folder 771-774)
    - Issue 6 (microfilm), 1975
    - Issue 7, 1975; 3 (Box 58, Folder 775-777)
    - Issue 7 (continued), 1974-1976; 7 (Box 59, Folder 778-784)
    - Issue 7 (continued), 1974-1976; 2 (Box 60, Folder 785-786)
    - Issue 8, 1975-1976; 4 (Box 60, Folder 787-790)
    - Issue 8 (Continued), 1975-1976; 6 (Box 61, Folder 791-796)
    - Issue 9, 1977; 2 (Box 61, Folder 797-798)
    - Issue 10, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 799)
    - Issue 11, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 800)
    - Issue 12, 1980 (Box 62, Folder 801)
    - Issue 13, 1981 (Box 62, Folder 802)
    - Unsorted production files, 1970-1978; 2 (Box 62, Folder 803-804)
  - Administrative Records
    - Subscriptions, 1971-1976; 2 (Box 62, Folder 805-806)
    - Copyrights, 1972-1975 (Box 62, Folder 807)
    - Permission to reprint, 1970-1974 (Box 62, Folder 808)
    - Financial reports, 1974-1975 (Box 62, Folder 809)
    - Budget memoranda, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 810)
    - Grants, 1974-1975 (Box 62, Folder 811)
    - Invoices and receipts, 1970-1977; 4 (Box 63, Folder 812-815)
    - Travel requests, 1971-1976 (Box 63, Folder 816)
- Personal Papers, 1905-1984; Series IV; 1.04; (3 boxes)
  Series IV consists of the personal papers of Norman Macleod, including vital records, educational records, employment records, curricula vitae, bibliographies, and financial, insurance and medical papers.
  - Birth certificates and baptism papers, photocopies, 1977 (Box 64, Folder 817)
  - High School and college transcripts, 1927-1967 (Box 64, Folder 818)
  - Teaching certificates, 1959-1972 (Box 64, Folder 819)
  - Curricula vitae, 1931-1969; 2 (Box 64, Folder 820-821)
  - "Records II and III" (biographical information and bibliography), 1935-1939, undated; 2 (Box 64, Folder 822-823)
  - "Index of work published by Norman Wicklund Macleod", 1935 (Box 64, Folder 824)
  - Press release and exhibition checklist, Pembroke State University, 1980 (Box 64, Folder 825)
  - Contracts and related papers, 1968-1983; 6 (Box 64, Folder 826-831)
  - Pembroke State University resignation papers, 1973-1977 (Box 64, Folder 832)
  - Awards and certificates, 1939-1978; 2 (Box 64, Folder 833-834)
  - Royalty statements, 1940, 1980 (Box 64, Folder 835)
  - Copyright records, 1974-1975 (Box 64, Folder 836)
  - Address-Appointment Book, 1962-1963 (Box 64, Folder 837)
  - Identification cards, 1951-1974 (Box 65, Folder 838)
  - Teachers College, Columbia University, record book, 1935-1950 (Box 65, Folder 839)
  - Financial records, 1965-1979; 4 (Box 65, Folder 840-843)
  - Medical and Insurance documents, 1971-1981; 2 (Box 65, Folder 844-845)
  - Papers, documents and notes related to Macleod's travels, 1964-1976; 3 (Box 65, Folder 846-848)
  - Postcards, 1971-1981; 2 (Box 65, Folder 849-850)
  - Memorabilia, 1909-1974; 5 (Box 66, Folder 851-855)
  - University Nursing Center ephemera, 1983-1984; 2 (Box 66, Folder 856-857)
  - Cloth calendar, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 858)
- Family Papers, 1905-1981; Series V; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Family Papers includes clippings, articles, vital records, and other papers relating to Norman Wicklund Macleod's family members.
  - Alice Wicklund Mills papers, 1905-1981; 8 (Box 67, Folder 859-866)